Guide to the Academics and Research Reference Collection, 1851-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Academics and Research Reference collection 1851-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
1.25 linear feet Extent: approx. 1000 Items
The Academics and Research Reference Collection contains materials documenting academic and research matters at the University. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
UA.01.11.0078
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Academics and Research Reference Collection was acquired by the University Archives over time.
Collection Overview
The collection contains documents pertaining to academic and research matters at the University such as curriculum development, advising, academic and research support, interdisciplinary programs, consortia and cooperative programs, research centers, and so forth. The materials include handbooks, clippings, flyers, reports, and proposals. The bulk dates are 1964-1994.
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Academic calendars and examination schedules, 1976-2000 (Box 1)
  - Academic Plan, Duke University - Working Draft, Vol. I / Office of the Provost, 1987 [there was no Volume II and no final version] (Box 1)
  - Academic Programs at Duke [brochure, undated, 1980s] (Box 1)
  - Advising: Duke Network, etc. (Box 1)
  - Advising: health professions, 1979-1986 (Box 1)
  - Advising: pre-Law, 1972, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Advising: Pre-Major Advising Center, 1980-1994 (Box 1)
  - Advising: pre-Major Advising Center -handbooks & advisors' manuals, 1986-1994 (Box 1)
  - Animal care facility (Vivarium), 1974 (Box 1)
  - Army Research Office, Durham, 1979-2001 (Box 1)
  - Bass Program, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Center for Academic Integrity, 1998- (Box 1)
  - Curricula: house courses, student lectures and seminars, 1981- (Box 1)
  - Curricula: interdisciplinary studies, 1964- (Box 1)
  - Curricula: Latin-American studies, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Curricula: teacher training and education, 1851- (Box 1)
  - Degrees and majors, 1985-2001 (Box 1)
  - Directory of International Research and Training, Duke University, 1988-1989 [a listing of faculty] (Box 1)
  - Duke Futures Programs for Scholar-Interns, 1986-1989 (Box 1)
  - Duke Information Places, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Duke University Reading Center, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Educational Program Development Office, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Exchange programs, 1981- (Box 1)
  - Faculty Research Interests, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Grading and honors, 1978- (Box 2)
  - International programs, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Internships, assistantships, etc., 1972-1977 (Box 2)
  - Language laboratory, 1975-1987 (Box 2)
  - National Review Panel for Desegregation Research, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Oak Ridge National Laboratory, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Office of Research Support. Annotated Bibliography of Funding Information at Duke University, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Office of Research Support. External Funding Procedures: A Guide, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Office of Research Support. Newsletters, 1983-1987 (Box 2)
  - Office of Research Support. Research administration and sponsored program information for new faculty, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Peace Studies, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Preschool and Primary Program, 1973, 1982-1984 (Box 2)
  - Programs: Daedalus [before 1964] (Box 2)
  - Programs: Preparing minorities for academic careers, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Programs: Pre-college, 1979-1984 (Box 2)
  - Programs: Program II, 1968-1980 (Box 2)
  - Research with Human Subjects: A Manual for Investigators, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Science Research Center [Levine], 1991 (Box 2)
  - Space research, 1962-1964 (Box 3)
  - Study abroad, 1978- (Box 3)
  - Summer Educational Programs Office, circa 1977-1982 (Box 3)
  - Summer session, 1990-1997 (Box 3)
  - Summer Transitional Program, 1969-1980 (Box 3)
  - Talent Identification Program, 1987- (Box 3)
  - Triangle Universities Center for Advanced Studies (TUCASI) (Box 3)
  - Triangle Universities Center for Advanced Studies (TUCASI) -- Charles Babbage Institute proposal, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Triangle Universities Computation Center (TUCC), 1969-1989 (Box 3)
  - Triangle Universities East Asian Center (Box 3)
  - Triangle Universities Nuclear Laboratory, 1969, 1975, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Undergraduate education (Box 3)
  - Whitehead Institute for Biomedical Research, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Young Writers' Camp, 1984-1987 (Box 3)